auburn.edu 2019-08-21

# Auburn University | Privacy Statement

Auburn University respects both the privacy of individuals who use its websites and the privacy and security of the information they provide to the University. The University is committed to ensuring the security of your sensitive and confidential information.  We are committed to having reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards designed to prevent unauthorized access to or use of the information we collected online.

Please note, that many units of the University run and maintain their own websites on the auburn.edu domain.  These sites may provide additional information relating to the information they collect related to your web browsing experience, which may supplement this Privacy Statement.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small file placed onto your device that enables features and functionality. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. 

Most pages on the auburn.edu domain utilize a technology known as Google Analytics. This technology places cookies on user computers that allow us to gather general statistics regarding how our websites are used.  For example, if we know what browser software and screen resolution our users are utilizing, we are better able to design web pages that suit our users.  The statistics we generate are aggregate. We do not track the usage patterns of individual users.

Please visit the [Google Analytics website](https://www.google.com/analytics) for more information.

If you choose not to accept cookies from our site using the consent banner, our website will create an opt-out cookie which will be stored in your browser folder which will block future Google Analytic cookies from being installed on your browser from our website. You can also manage cookies by activating the setting on your Internet browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies.  If you turn off cookies, this may change your browsing experience in some cases.  Google Analytics also offers a browser add-on (available for most browsers) which allows users to prevent their data from being used by their services across all sites.

### Other Data Collection

Auburn University web servers collect information such as the IP address of your computer, the operating system, browser software used, access times, and pages visited.  This data is used statistically and in aggregate to monitor web server performance, network security and to help manage the site and improve service.

As a general rule, Auburn University does not track individual visitor profiles, but does reserve the right to use log data to investigate resource management or security concerns.

Visitors using online forms or applications on our web pages may choose to supply information voluntarily. Information collected via such web forms will be securely maintained and be used only for the purposes for which it was supplied. Pages collecting such information should be transparent about the information they are collecting as well as the purpose for the data collection.

Auburn University policy does not allow the release of personally identifiable information to third parties (other than its agents when required for university business) except with permission of the person identified or as allowed or required by law.

This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to Auburn University ("AU") by prospective undergraduate and graduate students and applicants. Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.

For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.

### Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data

AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.

Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:

  * Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
  * Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
  * Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
  * Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.

There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.

### Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose

Enrollment Services and the Graduate School collect the following categories of Personal Data in order to recruit and admit undergraduate and graduate students:

  * Name
  * Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data
  * Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date of birth)
  * Details of your educational qualifications
  * _Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws_
  * _Financial information gathered for the purposes of verifying eligibility for study in the United States_
  * Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University 

The Personal Data that Enrollment Services and the Graduate School collect may be shared internally with academic units, Alumni Affairs and other school officials with a legitimate educational interest.

If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by Enrollment Services, please contact the Director, Enrollment Services-Operations at (334) 844-6420. For questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by the Graduate School, please contact the Dean of the Graduate School at (334) 844-4700. 

If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.

### Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data

Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, Enrollment Services and the Graduate School may collect data from ACT, College Board, Cappex, ETS, and the State of Alabama Statewide Transfer & Articulation Reporting System (STARS) and other entities in accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA).

### Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR

In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:

  * Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
  * Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
  * The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
  * Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
  * If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
  * If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
  * Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
  * Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.

Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.

Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:  
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy  
304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849  
(334) 844-4389

### Cookies

Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website [Privacy Statement](http://www.auburn.edu/privacy).

### Security of Personal Data

All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in [Auburn University's Policies Database](http://auburn.edu/policies) as they are amended from time-to-time.  
Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:

  * as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
  * as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
  * with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.

### Data Retention

Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the [Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority](http://www.lib.auburn.edu/specialcollections/docs/pdf/universities-general-rda-2017-05-24-1.pdf).

This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to the Auburn University ("AU") Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy ("OACP") by non-AU subscribers to _Case in Point: Lessons for the proactive manager_. Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU. 

For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.

### Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data

AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.

Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:

  * Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
  * Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
  * Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
  * Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.

There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.

### Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose

OACP collects the following categories of Personal Data, with your consent, in order to fulfil external (non-AU) requests to be added to our monthly newsletter (" _Case in Point: Lessons for the proactive manager_ "):

  * Your email address
  * The following information is requested but you may choose not to provide it:
    * Your Name
    * Your job title
    * Your place of employment

The Personal Data that OACP collects as part of this subscription process will be saved to our service provider's ( _[Constant Contact](https://www.endurance.com/privacy)_ ) databases in order to manage our subscription lists and facilitate the sending of our newsletter. We may also share your information among OACP management in order to evaluate and improve our subscription reach.  
If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by OACP, please contact the Robert Gottesman, Director Institutional Compliance & Privacy at 334.844.4389  
If you refuse to provide your email address it will be impossible for OACP to provide you with a subscription to our newsletter: _Case In Point_. Access to newsletter content may still be obtained via our website.

### Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data

Auburn University OACP receives personal and sensitive Personal Data, for the purpose of sending our newsletter from the data subject directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. 

### Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR

In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:

  * Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
  * Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
  * The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
  * Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
  * If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
  * If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
  * Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
  * Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.

Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.

Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:  
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy  
304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849  
(334) 844-4389

### Cookies

Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website [Privacy Statement](http://www.auburn.edu/privacy).

### Security of Personal Data

All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in [Auburn University's Policies Database](http://auburn.edu/policies) as they are amended from time-to-time.  
Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:

  * as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
  * as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
  * with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.

### Data Retention

Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the [Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority](http://www.lib.auburn.edu/specialcollections/docs/pdf/universities-general-rda-2017-05-24-1.pdf).

This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to Auburn University ("AU") by EMPLOYEES.  Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.

For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.

### Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data

AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.

Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:

  * Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
  * Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
  * Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
  * Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.

There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.

### Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose

Human Resources collects the following categories of Personal Data in order to establish and maintain an employment relationship in compliance with federal and state laws, as well as Auburn University policies and benefit programs.

  * Name
  * Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data
  * Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date of birth)
  * Details of your education and/or employment qualifications
  * Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
  * Information of dependents for benefit plan administration
  * Contact information including, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data of personal references for employment purposes.
  * Financial information gathered for the purposes of verifying eligibility for study in the United States
  * Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University

The Personal Data that HUMAN RESOURCES collects may be shared with:

  * Human resource administration internally for in the facilitation of resource related policies and processes to include (e.g. payroll, leave), organizational management, benefit administration, compensation management, professional development, performance management, as well as any employment related correspondence.
  * Companies or organizations providing specific services to, or on behalf of, the University, such as criminal, sex offender, driving and education background checks (background checks are conducted as a condition of employment)
  * Federal and/or State regulatory agencies
  * Any relevant professional or state agency or organization
  * Third parties the University has contracted with to assist with benefits administration, onboarding processes, performance management and/or other related HR services
  * Court officials to adhere to court mandates or legal obligations
  * Internal and external organizations to produce statistics and research for internal and statutory/regulatory reporting purposes
  * Agencies and trusted advisers in order to receive professional advice or guidance in relation to a number of matters (e.g. legal and audit services, fee status verification) or to provide services to you through a third party on our behalf
  * our online directory
  * Other than as set out above, we will not normally publish or disclose any personal information about you to other external enquirers or organizations unless you have requested it or consented to it, we are legally obligated to do so, or unless it is in your vital interest (e.g. in an emergency situation)

If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by HUMAN RESOURCES, please contact the Marketing and Communication Specialist, 1550 East Glen Avenue, Auburn, AL 36830 or (334) 844-4145.  
If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.

### Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data

Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, Human Resources collects data from:

  * Third parties the University partners with to assist in benefits administration, background check facilitation and in the management of Auburn University policies and procedures 

### Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR

In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:

  * Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
  * Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
  * The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
  * Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
  * If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
  * If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
  * Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
  * Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.

Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.

Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:  
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy  
304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849  
(334) 844-4389

### Cookies 

Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website [Privacy Statement](http://www.auburn.edu/privacy).

### Security of Personal Data 

All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in [Auburn University's Policies Database](http://auburn.edu/policies) as they are amended from time-to-time.

Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:

  * as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
  * as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
  * with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.

### _Data Retention_

Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the [Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority](http://www.lib.auburn.edu/specialcollections/docs/pdf/universities-general-rda-2017-05-24-1.pdf).

This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to Auburn University ("AU") by **Employee Applicant(s)**. Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.

For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.

### Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data

AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.

Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:

  * Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
  * Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
  * Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
  * Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.

There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.

### Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose

Human Resources collects the following categories of Personal Data in order to process information necessary for recruitment and selection decisions or necessary for compliance with a legal obligation:

  * Name
  * Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data
  * Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date of birth)
  * Details of your education and/or employment qualifications
  * Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
  * Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University 
  * Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data of personal and professional references (provided on application materials)

The Personal Data that AU collects may be shared on an as needed basis with:

  * Appropriate employees at the University during recruitment and selection processes
  * Professional and personal references provided on application materials
  * Companies or organizations providing specific services to, or on behalf of, the University for recruitment and selection purposes to include, criminal, driving and academic background checks (background checks are conducted as a condition of employment)
  * Appropriate government agencies

If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data collected as part of non-faculty employment application by Human Resources, please contact the Marketing and Communication Specialist, 1550 East Glen Avenue, Auburn, AL 36830 or (334) 844-4145, for questions about the data collected as part of a faculty employee application please contact the Special Assistant to the Provost for Human Resources, 208 Samford Hall, Auburn, AL 36849 or (334) 844-4000.

If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.

### Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data

Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, AU collects data from 

  * Companies or organizations providing specific services to, or on behalf of, the University for recruitment and selection purposes to include, criminal, driving and academic background checks

### Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR

In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:

  * Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
  * Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
  * The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
  * Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
  * If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
  * If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
  * Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
  * Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.

Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.

Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:  
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy  
304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849  
(334) 844-4389

### Cookies

Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website [Privacy Statement](http://www.auburn.edu/privacy).

### Security of Personal Data

All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in [Auburn University's Policies Database](http://auburn.edu/policies) as they are amended from time-to-time.

Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:

  * as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
  * as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
  * with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.

### Data Retention

Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the [Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority](http://www.lib.auburn.edu/specialcollections/docs/pdf/universities-general-rda-2017-05-24-1.pdf).

This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to Auburn University ("AU") by current or former students.  Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.

For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.

### Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data

AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.

Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:

  * Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
  * Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
  * Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
  * Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.

There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.

### Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose

The Office of the Registrar collects the following categories of Personal Data in order to maintain the accuracy of student records:

  * Name
  * Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data
  * Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date of birth)
  * Details of your education 
  * Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
  * Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University 

The Personal Data that the Office of the Registrar collects may be shared with other school officials with a legitimate educational interest. In the interest of complying with Federal and State legal requirements, as well as performing services for the institution, Personal Data may be shared with third party partners, vendors, accreditors, and agencies, including but not limited to, the Alabama Commission of Higher Education, the National Student Clearinghouse, and the State of Alabama and other entities in accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA).

If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by the Office of the Registrar, please contact the University Registrar at [registrar@auburn.edu](mailto:registrar@auburn.edu).

If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.

### Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data

Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, the Office of the Registrar collects receives data from other educational institutions.

### Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR

In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:

  * Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
  * Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
  * The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
  * Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
  * If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
  * If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
  * Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
  * Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.

Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.

Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:  
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy  
304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849  
(334) 844-4389

### Cookies

Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website [Privacy Statement](http://www.auburn.edu/privacy).

### Security of Personal Data

All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in [Auburn University's Policies Database](http://auburn.edu/policies) as they are amended from time-to-time.

Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:

  * as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
  * as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
  * with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.

### Data Retention

Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the [Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority](http://www.lib.auburn.edu/specialcollections/docs/pdf/universities-general-rda-2017-05-24-1.pdf).

This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to the Auburn University ("AU") Office of International Programs by prospective students, students, former students, potential visiting scholars, visiting scholars, potential employees and employees.  Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.

For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.

### Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data

AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.

Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:

  * Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
  * Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
  * Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
  * Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.

There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.

### Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose

The Office of International Programs collects the following categories of Personal Data in order to process immigration documentation as required by the U.S. government; to enroll students in study abroad and/or exchange programs; and/or to facilitate and coordinate emergency assistance for AU students and personnel on AU programs/business abroad:

  * Name
  * Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, other location data and emergency contact information
  * Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date and place of birth)
  * Dependent information if dependents are accompanying the Data Subject during travel abroad and/or to the U.S.
  * Details of your education and/or employment qualifications
  * Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
  * Financial information gathered for the purposes of verifying eligibility for study in the United States
  * Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University

The Personal Data that the Office of International Programs collects may be shared with AU departments including Admissions, the Office of the Registrar, the Office of Risk Management, the Office of Campus Safety and Security, the Graduate School, Student Financial Services, academic and administrative departments, Human Resources and Housing; and with external organizations such as the Department of Homeland Security, Customs and Border Patrol, the U.S. Department of State, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, the Veterans Administration, Alabama Secretary of State and PACT offices, Auburn Global, insurance companies contracted to serve AU students and personnel in emergencies overseas. This information may also be stored in software licensed by AU for the purposes stated above.

If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by the Office of International Programs, please contact the assistant provost for international programs at [intledu@auburn.edu](mailto:intledu@auburn.edu).

If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.

### Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data

Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, the Office of International Programs collects data from Auburn Global.

### Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR

In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:

  * Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
  * Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
  * The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
  * Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
  * If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
  * If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
  * Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
  * Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.

Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.

Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:  
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy  
304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849  
(334) 844-4389

### Cookies

Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website [Privacy Statement](http://www.auburn.edu/privacy).

### Security of Personal Data

All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in [Auburn University's Policies Database](http://auburn.edu/policies) as they are amended from time-to-time.

Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:

  * as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
  * as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
  * with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.

### Data Retention

Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the [Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority](http://www.lib.auburn.edu/specialcollections/docs/pdf/universities-general-rda-2017-05-24-1.pdf).
